An unforgettable journey she probably won't remember.
Finding Dory is a adventure, animation, comedy film directed by Andrew Stanton.
Dory is reunited with her friends Nemo and Marlin in
the search for answers about her past.
What can she remember?
Who are her parents?
And where did she learn to speak Whale?
Marlin (voice), played by Albert Brooks.
Dory (voice), played by Ellen DeGeneres.
Hank (voice), played by Ed O'Neill.
Nemo (voice), played by Hayden Rolence.
Jenny (voice), played by Diane Keaton.
Charlie (voice), played by Eugene Levy.
Finding Dory is a 2016 American animated comedy-drama adventure film
produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
It was directed by Andrew Stanton, co-directed by Angus MacLane, produced by
Lindsey Collins, and written by Stanton and Victoria Strouse.
The film is both a sequel and spin-off following
the events of Finding Nemo (2003).
Ellen DeGeneres (in her final film role prior to her retirement in 2024) and Albert Brooks reprise their roles from the first film, with Ed
O'Neill, Kaitlin Olson, Hayden Rolence (replacing Alexander Gould), Ty Burrell, Diane Keaton and Eugene Levy joining the cast.
The film focuses on the amnesiac fish Dory (DeGeneres), who journeys
to be reunited with her parents (Keaton and Levy).
Disney planned to make a sequel to Finding Nemo since 2005, tasking its new
studio Circle Seven Animation after disagreements with Pixar.
Though it never went into production, a script was uploaded to the official Raindance
Film Festival website that includes elements of the unmade script.
Disney's acquisition of Pixar in early 2006 led to the
cancellation of Circle Seven's version of the film.
A Pixar-made sequel was announced in April 2013 as the
schedule for a November 2015 release.
The fictional Marine Life Institute depicted extensively in the film is based on the production team's
research trips to the Monterey Bay Aquarium, the Marine Mammal Center and the Vancouver Aquarium.
Thomas Newman returned to compose the score.
Finding Dory premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on June 8, 2016,
and was released in theaters in the United States on June 17.
It received widespread praise from critics, like its predecessor, for
its animation, emotional weight, voice acting and humor.
The film earned $1.029 billion worldwide, finishing its theatrical run as the
third-highest-grossing film of 2016 and the fourth-highest-grossing animated film at the time.
It set numerous box office records, including the biggest opening for an animated film in Canada and the
United States and the highest-grossing animated film in Canada and the United States.
The film received a win at the 2017 Kids' Choice Awards for Favorite
Animated Movie, among various other awards at various shows.
The film explores themes of fish, amnesia, octopus, sequel, anthropomorphism.
The tone is lighthearted.